# **Abdoulage SAYOUTI SOULEYMANE**

R&D Artificial Intelligence Engineer at Aiway

Portfolio https://abdoulaye-sayouti.github.io/

# Personal Info

## Profil

Driven Al engineer with 2+ years' experience building NLP models and working on 3D data processing. Has a strong background in software development and telecommunications. Fluent in French and English; I also contribute to Open Source initiatives within the AI community.

# Work Experience & Projects

#### 2022-10 Aiway, Aix-en-Provence

**Present** R&D Artificial Intelligence Engineer

- · Audit of models developed in the dental field in order to identify, correct and improve shortcomings in the process of data preparation, training and evaluation of these
- Development of a python library for adapting planned digital building models (BIM IFC) to reflect the as-built state of the structure.
- Technologies: Python, Open3D, PyTorch3D, IfcOpenShell, BIMcollab ZOOM, MeshLab, Scikit-Learn & GitLab

#### 2021-06 Enedis Al Lab, Marseille

2022-09 Artificial Intelligence Engineer Apprentice

- Text and time series data processing.
- · Technology watch, development of various models (text classification, NER, text generation and auto-completion), then deployment of these models in production.
- Technologies: Python, PyTorch, NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, RegEx, CamemBERT, BARThez, PostgreSQL, Flask, Docker, CodeCarbon & GitLab

### 2020-05 Infineon Technologies Padova, Italy

2020-09 Data Analyst Intern

- Design and development of a dashboard for real-time visualization and validation of the company's software, firmware and hardware development processes, in compliance with ISO 26262 "Road vehicles - Functional safety" and Automotive SPICE standards.
- Technologies: Python, MySQL, Logstash, Elasticsearch, Kibana, Balsamiq Wireframe, Jenkins.

#### 2021-03 School projects

2021-06 Hadoop & Rasa Open Source

- Development of a Voice Chatbot and interfacing with Pepper and NAO robots using the Rasa Open Source framework and Coregraphe Suite.
- Distributed implementation of the K-means clustering algorithm using Hadoop's MapReduce parallel programming paradigm.

#### **Education**

#### 2020-10 Center for Education and Research in Computer Science (CERI)

- 2022-06 M.Sc in Artificial Intelligence, Avignon University
- 2019-09 University of Padova, Italy
- 2020-09 ERASMUS + M.Sc in ICT for Internet and Multimedia
- 2017-09 Higher School of Communication of Tunis, University of Carthage
- **2020-09** Engineer in Telecommunications
- 2016-09 National School of Electronics and Telecoms, University of Sfax
- 2017-06 1st year M.Sc in Information and Communications Technology

#### 2013-09 Faculty of Sciences of Gabes, University

2016-06 B.Sc in Computer Science

## **Paper & Certifications**

2023-08	HAPe: Optimizing Customer Relation by Automatic Task Distribution using Constrained
	Optimization and Natural Language Processing (CIRED 2023 - Enedis)

- 2020-11 Mathematics For Machine Learning Specialization (Coursera)
- 2019-11 Neural Network and Deep Learning (Coursera)
- 2019-05 98-369:MTA: Cloud Fundamentals (Microsoft)



Marseille, France



(+33) 7 49 82 75 89



abdoulaye.sayoutisouley mane@gmail.com



https://github.com/ GitHub Abdoulaye-Sayouti



https://www.linkedin.com/ in/sayouti-souleymaneabdoulave/

#### **Industries**

- Telecommunications.
- Electricity.
- Building information modeling (BIM).
- Dental.
- Semiconductor.

#### Skills

Machine Learning & Deep Learning

Natural Language Processing

3D data processing

MLOps, Docker & GitLab

Python & Scikit-Learn

PyTorch & TensorFlow

Transformers & RegEx

Hadoop & Talend

lacktriangle

Data Visualization, Tableau & ELK Stack

PostgreSQL & AWS

C, C++ & Java

Linux/Unix & Matlab

**•**••••

JavaScript, NodeJs, Flask & PHP



## Languages

French

English (B2)